Guide to the William Kenneth Boyd Papers, 1851 - 1956 UA.29.02.0075
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Kenneth Boyd papers
1851 - 1956
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Boyd, William Kenneth, 1879-1938
UA.29.02.0075
20 Linear Feet
William Kenneth Boyd (1879-1938) was a historian, professor, and director of the library at Duke University. During his career at Duke and Trinity College, he published widely and helped to collect and preserve personal papers and books about Southern and North Carolina history. The William Kenneth Boyd papers include correspondence, diaries, financial and legal materials, writings, notes, student papers, photographs (including tintypes), and other materials related to the personal and professional life of Boyd. Major correspondents include N. B. McDowell, Pat LeGrand, Marion Colley, and John Spencer Bassett. There are also letters from W. E. B. Du Bois and other prominent African Americans. English.
20000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The William Kenneth Boyd Papers were received by the University Archives as gifts from 1948-1978.
Biographical Note
William Kenneth Boyd was born on January 10, 1879, in Curryville, Missouri, the son of Reverend Harvey Marshall and Mary Elizabeth Black Boyd. He grew up in Weaverville, North Carolina. Boyd began attending Trinity College (later part of Duke University) in Durham, North Carolina in 1895, and he received an A.B. degree in 1897 and an M.A. degree in 1898. He served as an assistant to Professor John Spencer Bassett while he completed his M.A. degree, and he then worked as a history teacher at Trinity Park School, a high school on the Trinity College campus. From 1900 to 1902, Boyd was an adjunct professor of history at Trinity College.
After receiving his Ph.D. from Columbia University in 1906, Boyd returned to teach at Trinity College. He had a strong interest in regional and southern history, and published extensively on these topics. Among his publications were A Selected Bibliography and Syllabus of the History of the South, 1584-1876 (with Robert P. Brooks), A Syllabus of North Carolina History, 1584-1896 (with J. G. deRoulhac Hamilton), The Federal Period, 1783-1860 (part of a three volume set on North Carolina history), and The Story of Durham, City of the New South. He also co-edited the South Atlantic Quarterly from 1919-1929, a journal founded by his mentor, Bassett.
In addition to his historical writing and teaching, Boyd actively collected materials for the library. Through the funding of the Flowers family, he made the Flowers Collection of southern Americana one of the pre-eminent collections of manuscript and research materials in the country. Boyd served as director of the libraries from 1930 to 1934. In addition to purchasing materials, he encouraged his students to look for materials in their own homes and hometowns that could be added to Trinity College's and later Duke University's collections.
Boyd died on January 19, 1938. He was married to Pat LeGrand from 1908 until 1924, when she passed away. The couple had one daughter, Mary Elizabeth, who married Duke history professor William B. Hamilton in 1938. William Kenneth Boyd remarried in 1931 to journalist Marion Colley.
Collection Overview
The William Kenneth Boyd papers include correspondence, diaries, financial and legal materials, writings, notes, student papers, photographs (including tintypes), and other materials related to the personal and professional life of Boyd. The collection is arranged into seven series.
The first series, Personal, includes family materials like diaries, financial and legal materials, and other family writings. The diaries were written by Boyd's first wife and his daughter. The second series, Correspondence, includes personal, History Department, and Library and Flowers Collection correspondence. Major personal correspondents include N.B. McDowell, Pat LeGrand, Marion Colley, and John Spencer Bassett. Of particular interest in the personal correspondence are some letters Boyd exchanged with prominent African-Americans, including W. E. B. Du Bois, in 1899. The History Department and Library and Flowers Collection correspondence discuss research and administrative activities in these two areas of Duke University.
The third series, Writings, includes published and unpublished articles and books by Boyd. The fourth series, Notes, includes research and lecture notes taken by Boyd. The topics of both Writings and Notes tend to be about Southern and specifically North Carolina history. The next series, Teaching, primarily includes student papers about Southern and North Carolina history. The Library series includes administrative papers from when Boyd directed the library at Duke. The last series, Photographs, features family photographs, most of which are tintypes in excellent condition.
Related Material
George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana
Rare Books, Manuscripts, and Special Collections Library, Duke University
George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana records
Duke University Archives
Southern States -- History -- 20th century; Photographs; Tintypes (prints); North Carolina -- History -- 19th century; North Carolina -- History -- 20th century; Manuscripts -- Collectors and collecting -- North Carolina; Race relations -- History -- 20th century; Southern States -- History -- 19th century; Diaries; Race relations -- History -- 19th century; Duke University. Department of History -- Faculty; Boyd, Pat LeGrand; Duke University. Library; Boyd, William Kenneth, 1879-1938; Duke University -- Faculty; Boyd, William Kenneth, 1879-1938; Duke University -- Students; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963; McDowell, Nannie Black; Bassett, John Spencer, 1867-1928; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Faculty; Boyd family
- Personal, 1866-1946
  Scope and Contents note
  The Personal series contains the personal and family materials of William Kenneth Boyd. Included are financial and legal materials; diaries written by Boyd's first wife, Pat LeGrand and his daughter, Mary Elizabeth Boyd; materials related to Boyd's funeral; and pieces of creative writing. Materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Account book, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Account books, circa 1936, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Childhood writings, 1888-1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Desk book, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diary of Mary Elizabeth Boyd, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diary of Mary Elizabeth Boyd, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diary of Pat LeGrand Boyd, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Drawings and maps, undated (Oversize-box 41, Folder 8)
  - Early Printers' Marks by Mary Elizabeth Boyd, circa 1930-1939 (Oversize-box 41, Folder 9)
  - Family history (Oversize-box 41, Folder 10)
  - Financial documents, 1866-1922 (Oversize-box 41, Folder 11)
  - Legal documents, 1885-1939 (Oversize-box 41, Folder 12)
  - List of wedding presents, by Pat Le Grand (Oversize-box 41, Folder 13)
  - Memorials for William K. Boyd, 1938 (Oversize-box 41, Folder 14)
  - Poetry and stories, undated (Oversize-box 41, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1851-1956
  The Correspondence series is arranged into three main sections. The first section, Personal, contains correspondence to and from Boyd with family members and friends. His aunt, N. B. McDowell, a faculty member at Weaverville College, wrote to Boyd frequently while he attended Trinity College and afterward. Boyd also corresponded frequently with his first wife, Pat LeGrand, second wife, Marion Colley, and mentor, John Spencer Bassett. The correspondence for the latter two is filed separately in folders at the end of the personal correspondence. The rest of the materials are arranged chronologically. Of note in this section are letters Boyd sent and received from prominent African-Americans, including W. E. B. Du Bois, in 1899.
  The second section of the correspondence is History Department correspondence, sent and received while Boyd was a faculty member in the Duke Department of History. It includes letters sent to and from members of the Duke History Department as well as historians at other institutions. The correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  The third section is Library and Flowers Collection correspondence, and mainly stems from Boyd's service as director of the library at Duke. Most of the letters document Boyd's attempt to purchase or otherwise acquire personal papers and rare books from individuals and dealers across the South. These materials are arranged chronologically.
  - Personal
    - 1851-1882 (Oversize-box 41, Folder 16)
    - 1883 (Oversize-box 41, Folder 17)
    - 1884-1891 (Oversize-box 41, Folder 18)
    - 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - January 1896-May 1896 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - September 1896-October 1896 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - November 1896-December 1896 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - January 1897-February 1897 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - March 1897-May 1897 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - June 1897-September 1897 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - October 1897-December 1897 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - January 1898-February 1898 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - March 1898-April 1898 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - May 1898-June 1898 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - August 1898-October 1898 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - November 1898-December 1898 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - January 1899-March 1899 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - April 1899-December 1899 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - January 1900-June 1900 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - July 1900-June 1901 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - September 1901-December 1901 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - January 1902-May 1902 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - July 1902-December 1902 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - January 1903-July 1903 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - August 1903-December 1903 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - January 1904-March 1904 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - April 1904-June 1904 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - July 1904-December 1904 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - January 1905-April 1905 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - May 1905-December 1905 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - February 1906-September 1906 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - October 1906-December 1906 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - January 1907-June 1907 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - July 1907 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - August 1907 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - September 1907 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - October 1907 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - November 1907 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - December 1907 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - January 1908 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - February 1908 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - March 1908 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - April 1908 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - May 1908 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - June 1908 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - July 1908 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - August 1908 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - September 1908 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - October 1908 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - November 1908 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - December 1908 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - 1909 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - 1910 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - 1911-1912 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - 1913-1914 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - 1915 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - 1916-1917 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - 1918 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - 1919 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - 1920 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - 1921 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - 1922-1923 (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - February 1924, July 1924 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - August 1924 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - September 1924 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - October 1924-November 1929 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - February 1930-February 1956 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Undated (Box 8, Folder 83-84)
    - John Spencer Bassett, October 1904-April 1926 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Marion T. Colley, July 1930-December 1930 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - History Department
    - 1898-1906 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - 1907-1908 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - 1909-1911 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - 1912 (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - 1913 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - 1914 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - 1915 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - 1916 (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - 1917 (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - January 1918-June 1918 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - July 1918-December 1918 (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - January 1919-June 1919 (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - July 1919-December 1919 (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - 1920 (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - 1921 (Box 10, Folder 101)
    - January 1922-June 1922 (Box 10, Folder 102)
    - July 1922-December 1922 (Box 10, Folder 103)
    - January 1923-June 1923 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - July 1923-December 1923 (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - 1924 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - 1925 (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - 1926 (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - January 1927-February 1927 (Box 11, Folder 109)
    - March 1927 (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - April 1927 (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - May 1927-October 1927 (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - November 1927 (Box 12, Folder 113)
    - December 1927-January 1928 (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - February 1928-March 1928 (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - April 1928-May 1928 (Box 12, Folder 116)
    - June 1928-December 1928 (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - January 1929-February 1929 (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - March 1929-April 1929 (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - May 1929-September 1929 (Box 12, Folder 120)
    - October 1929-December 1929 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    - January 1930-February 1930 (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - March 1930 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - April 1930-May 1930 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - June 1930-July 1930 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - August 1930-September 1930 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - October 1930-December 1930 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - January 1931-April 1931 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - May 1931-August 1931 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    - September 1931-December 1931 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - January 1932-February 1932 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - March 1932-May 1932 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - June 1932-November 1932 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - December 1932-February 1933 (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - March 1933-August 1933 (Box 14, Folder 135)
    - September 1933-November 1933 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - December 1933-February 1934 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - March 1934-July 1934 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - August 1934-December 1934 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - January 1935-April 1935 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - May 1935-August 1935 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - September 1935-December 1935 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - January 1936-March 1936 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - April 1936-June 1936 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - July 1936-September 1936 (Box 15, Folder 145)
    - October 1936-December 1936 (Box 15, Folder 146)
    - January 1937-March 1937 (Box 16, Folder 147)
    - April 1937-January 1938 (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - Undated (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - Library and Flowers Collection
    - 1908-1920 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    - 1921 (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - 1922-1925 (Box 16, Folder 152)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 16, Folder 153)
    - 1928 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - January 1929-March 1929 (Box 16, Folder 155)
    - April 1929-June 1929 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    - July 1929-December 1929 (Box 17, Folder 157)
    - January 1930-March 1930 (Box 17, Folder 158)
    - April 1930-May 1930 (Box 17, Folder 159)
    - June 1930-July 1930 (Box 17, Folder 160)
    - August 1930-September 1930 (Box 17, Folder 161)
    - October 1930-December 1930 (Box 17, Folder 162)
    - January 1931-March 1931 (Box 17, Folder 163)
    - April 1931-May 1931 (Box 18, Folder 164)
    - June 1931-July 1931 (Box 18, Folder 165)
    - August 1931-September 1931 (Box 18, Folder 166)
    - October 1931-November 1931 (Box 18, Folder 167)
    - December 1931 (Box 18, Folder 168)
    - January 1932 (Box 18, Folder 169)
    - February 1932 (Box 18, Folder 170)
    - March 1932 (Box 19, Folder 171)
    - April 1932 (Box 19, Folder 172)
    - May 1932 (Box 19, Folder 173)
    - June 1932 (Box 19, Folder 174)
    - July 1932 (Box 19, Folder 175)
    - August 1932-October 1932 (Box 19, Folder 176)
    - November 1932 (Box 19, Folder 177)
    - December 1932 (Box 20, Folder 178)
    - January 1933-February 1933 (Box 20, Folder 179)
    - March 1933 (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - April 1933 (Box 20, Folder 181)
    - May 1933 (Box 20, Folder 182)
    - June 1933 (Box 20, Folder 183)
    - July 1933 (Box 20, Folder 184)
    - August 1933-September 1933 (Box 20, Folder 185)
    - October 1933 (Box 20, Folder 186)
    - November 1933 (Box 21, Folder 187)
    - December 1933 (Box 21, Folder 188)
    - January 1934 (Box 21, Folder 189)
    - February 1934-April 1934 (Box 21, Folder 190)
    - May 1934-July 1934 (Box 21, Folder 191)
    - August 1934-September 1934 (Box 21, Folder 192)
    - October 1934 (Box 21, Folder 193)
    - November 1934-December 1934 (Box 21, Folder 194)
    - January 1935 (Box 22, Folder 195)
    - February 1935-March 1935 (Box 22, Folder 196)
    - April 1935-May 1935 (Box 22, Folder 197)
    - June 1935 (Box 22, Folder 198)
    - July 1935-September 1935 (Box 22, Folder 199)
    - October 1935 (Box 22, Folder 200)
    - November 1935 (Box 22, Folder 201)
    - December 1935 (Box 22, Folder 202)
    - January 1936 (Box 22, Folder 203)
    - February 1936-March 1936 (Box 23, Folder 204)
    - April 1936-May 1936 (Box 23, Folder 205)
    - June 1936-August 1936 (Box 23, Folder 206)
    - September 1936-October 1936 (Box 23, Folder 207)
    - November 1936-December 1936 (Box 23, Folder 208)
    - January 1937-February 1937 (Box 23, Folder 209)
    - March 1937-April 1937 (Box 23, Folder 210)
    - May 1937-June 1937 (Box 23, Folder 211)
    - July 1937-August 1938 (Box 23, Folder 212)
    - Undated (Box 24, Folder 213-214)
- Writings, 1905-1938
  The Writings series includes published pieces, unpublished manuscripts, and drafts of Boyd's articles and books. His interest in southern, and especially North Carolina, history is evident in these materials, as is his interest in colonial America. The writings are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - The American Revolution and Reform in the South, 1923 (Box 24, Folder 215)
  - The Antecedents of the North Carolina Convention of 1835, 1910 (Box 24, Folder 216)
  - Bibliography of Tallyrand draft, undated (Box 24, Folder 217)
  - Boyd Family Journal, March 1925, November 1926 (Box 24, Folder 218)
  - Currency and Banking in North Carolina, 1790-1836, undated (Box 24, Folder 219)
  - Documents and Comments on Benefit of Clergy as Applied to slaves, October 1923 (Box 24, Folder 220)
  - Documents and Letters Concerning Lincoln and Fort Sumter, undated (Box 24, Folder 221)
  - Drafts on southern history and public education in Virginia, undated (Box 24, Folder 222)
  - The Ecclesiastical Edicts of the Theodosian Code, 1905 (Box 24, Folder 223)
  - English-American relations, undated (Box 24, Folder 224)
  - The Federal Period draft, undated (Box 24, Folder 225-226)
  - The Federal Period draft, undated (Box 25, Folder 227)
  - The Finances of the North Carolina Literary Fund, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 228)
  - The Flowers Collection draft, undated (Box 25, Folder 229)
  - History of N.C. Federal Period, undated (Box 25, Folder 230)
  - History of Trinity College draft, undated (Box 25, Folder 231-232)
  - History of Trinity College, undated (Box 25, Folder 233)
  - History of the South draft chapters, undated (Box 25, Folder 234-235)
  - Jeffersonian Ideals - Reform of the State Constitution, undated (Box 25, Folder 236)
  - The Literature of N.C. History draft, undated (Box 25, Folder 237)
  - Medieval Universities, undated (Box 25, Folder 238)
  - Memoirs of a Book Hunter, circa 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 239)
  - Methodist Expansion.. ., circa 1915 (Box 25, Folder 240)
  - Military Aspects of the Revolution, undated (Box 25, Folder 241)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 242)
  - The Movement for Public Education, undated (Box 26, Folder 243)
  - North Carolina on the Eve of Secession, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 244)
  - Pietism, Methodism, and the Great Awakening, undated (Box 26, Folder 245)
  - Religious Feeling in 18th-19th Centuries, undated (Box 26, Folder 246)
  - Robert E. Lee, undated (Box 26, Folder 247)
  - A Selected Bibliography and Syllabus of the History of the South, June 1918 (Box 26, Folder 248)
  - Slavery Debates, undated (Box 26, Folder 249)
  - Some Phases of Educational History in the South Since 1865, 1914 (Box 26, Folder 250)
  - The Story of Durham proof, circa 1925 (Box 26, Folder 251-252)
  - The Story of Durham proof, undated (Box 26, Folder 253)
  - A Syllabus of North Carolina History, 1584-1876, 1913 (with J.G. de Roulhac Hamilton) (Box 27, Folder 254)
  - Then and Now, March 1924 (Box 27, Folder 255)
  - W. W. Holden draft, undated (Oversize-box 41, Folder 256)
  - William W. Holden drafts, undated (Oversize-box 41, Folder 257)
- Notes, undated
  The Notes series includes primarily handwritten notes used by Boyd in his research and lectures. If there was any indication that the notes were used primarily for lecture or research, this has been indicated. Notes are arranged into Lecture, Research, and General sections, and alphabetically within these sections. Sometimes multiple subjects were filed together, and this arrangement has been preserved.
  Please note that many of these notes were taken on paper which is now fairly brittle. Patrons should use care in handling these materials.
  - Lecture
    - Emancipation, Lincoln, Civil War (Oversize-box 41, Folder 258)
    - English history, Virginia (Oversize-box 41, Folder 259-260)
    - English history, Reformation (Oversize-box 41, Folder 261-262)
    - English history, Reformation (Box 28, Folder 263-264)
    - Georgia, North Carolina, British Colonial System, Clergy (Box 28, Folder 265)
    - North Carolina, South Carolina, Slavery (Box 28, Folder 266-267)
    - Notes, 1870-1900 (Box 28, Folder 268)
    - Revolution in Virginia and North Carolina, the Durham area (Box 28, Folder 269-270)
    - Slavery (Box 29, Folder 271)
    - Slavery, Carolinas during pre-Constitutional and Constitutional periods (Box 29, Folder 272)
    - Slavery, Jay Treaty, and S.C. finance (Box 29, Folder 273)
    - Slavery, political and social theories of Thomas Jefferson (Box 29, Folder 274)
    - Southern history (Box 29, Folder 275)
    - Southern history and slavery (Box 29, Folder 276-277)
    - Spanish exploration and French Colonial System (Box 29, Folder 278)
    - Virginia, Jefferson, Jackson, War of 1812 (Box 30, Folder 279-282)
    - Virginia's social and religious development, English history (Box 30, Folder 283-284)
    - Virginia, South Carolina, manuscript list (Box 31, Folder 285-286)
  - Research
    - Jurisprudence notebook (Box 31, Folder 287)
    - North Carolina history notebook (Box 31, Folder 288)
    - Virginia (Box 31, Folder 289)
    - Virginia education, federal relations, and bibliography (Box 31, Folder 290)
    - Miscellaneous notebook (Box 31, Folder 291-293)
  - General
    - American History (Box 32, Folder 294)
    - Bibliographies, Southern history in the 1790s-1800s (Box 32, Folder 295)
    - Byron (Box 32, Folder 296)
    - Civil War (Box 32, Folder 297)
    - Cotton Revolution, slave economy (Box 32, Folder 298-299)
    - Education in the South (Box 32, Folder 300)
    - English History--17th century (Box 32, Folder 301)
    - English History--17th century (Box 33, Folder 302)
    - Jurisprudence, European law (Box 33, Folder 303)
    - Labor, 17th century (Box 33, Folder 304)
    - Monroe Doctrine, Bibliography of Economics of the Plantation (Box 33, Folder 305)
    - North Carolina, South Carolina (Box 33, Folder 306-307)
    - Outlines of North Carolina history, Southern history, Reconstruction (Box 33, Folder 308)
    - Lee Slater Overman (Box 33, Folder 309)
    - Population and wealth, North Carolina, South Carolina, Alabama (Box 33, Folder 310)
    - Post-Revolution history, financial situation, Articles of Confederation (Box 34, Folder 311-312)
    - Protestant Revolt (Box 34, Folder 313)
    - Revolution, causes of (Box 34, Folder 314)